Ryan Christopher DeYong

Website

텐GitHub

✓ Email

https://ryancdeyong.us

https://github.com/PerthGoat

+14408478142

administrator@ryancdeyong.us

I studied Computer Engineering at the University of Cincinnati. Throughout my work experience so far, I've been able to understand hardware and software requirements, and in addition collaborate with a team to achieve a viable end product. I'm passionate about electronics design work, low level software development, and algorithm design/optimization.

Experience

^{2018 - 2020} Intel 2021 - Present FIS

Software Engineering COOP

- Developed software with a team using the Agile software development model
- Created and demonstrated a prototype of a new technology to use in merchant processing
- Mentored other COOP students to help them better understand C# and JavaScript
- Worked directly with project stakeholders on deciding the direction of various projects

C#.NET ASP.NET SQL BOOtstrap JavaScript

Product Development Engineer

- Helped design and program testing automation software
- Worked on tokenizer and parser for internal programming language
- Interpreted analog oscilloscope readings to determine test correctness
- Significantly optimized algorithms resulting in up to a 15x performance boost in some cases
- Hacked Python internals to create IPC compatibility layer for old software

Skills

C#.NET | Compiler Theory | Python | LZ77

Radio/RF work

4+ years Circuit Design + CAD

4+ years GAN + CNN

2+ years

Frequent use

Executive of UC Amateur Radio Club (N8XZZ). RF/antenna circuit design for UC + Regal

Some use

Used CAD tools for building projects; circuit design for Regal,

UCARC, personal projects, VHDL

Some use

Custom PyTorch to create Generative Adversarial + Convolutional Networks

4+ years Linux **Reverse Engineering**

Frequent use

Reverse engineered compiled

Everyday use

Worked with Ghidra, GDB, ollydbg. System administration, web server Developed internal libraries and hosting, tool familiarity (gparted, internal Intel software to fix issues cat, ls, rm ...), FIFO, device files

5+ years Compiler Theory/NLP 2+ years

Frequent use

LL(1) parser for FIS; LALR(1) parser for Intel to fix parsing issues

Education

University of Cincinnati

April 2021 Westshore Career Technical

2014 - 2016

Bachelors of Science in Computer Engineering 3.4 GPA

Networking/Cisco Training Program 4.0 GPA

Location: Hillsboro, OR, USA

Willing to relocate